피비는 자기 부모님을
알고 있는 여자를 만났는데
Phoebe found out about this lady...
...who knew her parents,
and I don't know what happened.
어떻게 됐는지 모르겠고
I'm your mother.
내가 엄마다
모니카는 챈들러와 데이트를
하지 않겠다고 했는데
Monica joked she
wouldn't date Chandler.
안녕?
그쪽 사연도 어떻게
된 건지 모르겠고
I don't know what
happened there either.
Ross' new girlfriend shows up.
로스의 애인 보니는 레이첼
말을 듣고 머리를 밀었는데
Rachel gets Bonnie to shave her head.
Then they kiss.
로스와 레이첼의 키스!
레이첼과 대머리 여인
사이에서 방황하는 로스
Now he has to choose
Rachel or the bald girl.
I don't know what
happened there either.
거긴 또 어떻게 됐을까?
가서 챈들러를 데려오죠
Hold on.
Let me go get Chandler.
나야
왔어?
She's helping me.
My head's sunburned.
머리가 햇볕에 타서
크림 바르고 있어
- 정말 고마워
- 별말씀을 다 하시네
-Thanks a million.
-You're welcome a million.
맡아봐
Smell it.
음, 박하향이네
Minty.
I'll be in our room.
- 우리 방에 가있을게
- 그래
세상에...
Oh, my God!
알아
I know.
- 그래, 갈게
- 뭐야? 왜 그래?
I got to go.
보니랑 헤어져야 돼
I got to go break up with Bonnie.
Here? Now?
여기서? 지금?
밤새 있을 순 없잖아
저기 들어가면...
I can't stay here all night.
If I go in there, she'll want to...
뭘 하자고 할 거야
...do stuff.
- 안 내킨다고 하면 되지
- 그걸 더 좋아해
Can't you say
you aren't in the mood?
No, she likes that.
자는 척해도 소용없어
아침마다 같이 일어나면...
Faking sleep doesn't work.
I've woken up many times with her
알았어
-Why am I telling you?
-I don't know.
- 왜 이 말을 하지?
- 난들 알겠어?
-Not every morning
-Making it worse!
- 매일 아침은 아냐
- 그게 더 싫어
The One with the Jellyfish
You probably want to know
how it happened.
어떻게 된 건지
알고 싶을 거다
I think I can figure it out.
대충 짐작이 가요
모두 한통속이 돼서
날 호구로 만든 거죠
I was born, and then
everyone lied their asses off.
No, it wasn't like that.
그런 게 아니다
릴리와 프랭크, 내가
얼마나 가까웠는지 아니?
Remember how I said
Lilly, Frank and I were close?
아주 가까웠다
We were very close.
How close?
얼마나요?
우리 셋은 그러니까
커플이었어
The three of us were
kind of a couple.
I don't know how that would work.
그게 잘되던가요?
- 우린...
- 누가 물어봤어요?
I'm not asking!
어쩌다 임신이 됐고...
Anyhow, somehow I got pregnant...
...and I was...
두려웠다, 그땐 나밖에
모르는 바보였거든
...scared.
I was stupid and selfish....
I was 18 years old.
Remember what it was like to be 18?
18살이었어
너도 18살 때 기억하지?
네, 엄마는 자살하고
아빠는 달아나고
Mom killed herself
and my dad ran off.
난 자기 손하고 얘기하는
신디랑 그렘린에서 살았죠
I lived in a Gremlin with a guy
who talked to his hand.
I'm sorry. I thought I'd left you
with the best parents.
미안하다, 훌륭한 부모가
돼줄 거라 믿었는데
겨우 몇 년 전에 소식 들었다
넌 벌써 어른이 돼버렸고
I didn't hear about them
till a few years ago.
By then, you were already grown-up.
You're here and I would
really like to get to know you.
어떤 여자가 됐는지
정말 알고 싶구나
Well, everybody does.
다들 그렇대요
I'm a really cool person.
훌륭하게 자랐죠
29년 동안 아무 것도
하신 게 없잖아요
You had 29 years to find out,
but you didn't even try.
You walked out on me,
and I'll do the same.
나도 그냥 엄마를
포기할래요
- 얘야...
- 다신 보고 싶지 않아요
I don't ever want to see you again.
Where's my purse?
내 지갑 어딨죠?
Shoot! We're out of soda.
이런, 음료수가 떨어졌어
-I'll get you some.
-Really?
내가 사오지
- 진짜?
- 아니, 애인도 아닌데 왜?
No, because I'm not your boyfriend.
Hey, Pheebs, how'd it go?
어떻게 됐어?
엄마 친구 피비가
내 진짜 생모래
My mom's friend, Phoebe,
is actually my birth mom.
I found a dried-up seahorse.
말린 해마 먹을래?
그게 무슨 소리야?
What do you mean?
우리 엄마가
자식을 버렸다고
My new mom,
who's a big fat abandoner.
잠깐, 자세히 얘기 좀 해봐
Don't you want to stay here
and talk about it?
아니, 혼자 있고 싶어
I need to be alone.
모니카?
Man. Hey...
야, 만약 너희 엄마가
진짜 엄마가 아니고
...what if you found out that
your mom wasn't really your mom...
...and your new mom turned
out to be really hot?
새로 나타난 엄마가
엄청 새끈하다면 어쩔래
Oh, man, huh?
고거 참...
But, it's your mom.
하지만 너희 엄마잖아
No, I'm talking about your mom.
아니, 너희 엄마 얘기야
It's over.
끝났어
Was it awful?
- 힘들었지?
- 너무 지루하더라
It was long.
I didn't realize how late it was...
걔 머리통에 광이 나서
날이 샌 줄 알았다니까
...till I saw the five o'clock shadow
on her head.
She didn't want to stay.
I called a cab. She just left.
더 있고 싶지 않다면서
택시 불러서 방금 갔어
I wrote you a letter.
너한테 편지를 썼어
고마워
Oh, thank you!
I like mail.
난 우편물이 좋더라
It's just some things I've been
thinking about. About us.
우리 사이에 대해
줄곧 생각하던 거야
Before we even think about us
getting back together...
우리가 다시 합치기 전에
네 느낌을 알고 싶어서
...I need to know
how you feel about this stuff.
좋아
새벽 5시 반이야
It's 5:30 in the morning.
So I'd better get
cracking on this baby.
그럼 요 녀석부터
해결해볼까?
I'll be waiting for you.
Come up when you're done.
기다릴게
끝나면 올라와
그래, 알았어
I'll be up...
...in 18 pages.
18장이네요?
Front and back.
앞뒤로 꽉꽉!
기대가 커요
Very exciting!
뭐야, 왜 안 올라왔어?
What happened to you?
Why didn't you come up?
Done.
끝!
-You just finished?
-I wanted to be thorough.
- 지금 끝났어?
- 대충 읽을 수 있나
This is clearly
very important to you. To us.
너나 우리한테
중요한 일이잖아
I wanted to read
every word carefully.
모든 단어를 면밀하게
검토했지, 두 번씩
Twice.
어때... 그래?
Does it?
I'm sorry?
뭐가?
Does it?
그러냐고?
Does it? Does it?
그래, 그러냐고?
그럼 그런 부분을
다시 한번 보자
I wanted to give that whole
"Does it?" part another glance.
What do you mean?
You said you read it twice.
무슨 소리야?
두 번이나 읽었다며
그렇든 안 그렇든
시간이 필요하다면...
It either does or doesn't.
If you have to think
아냐, 생각할 필요도 없어
당연하지! 사실 말이야...
No, I don't have to think about it.
In fact...
...I've decided.
I have decided...
마음의 결정을 내렸어
그건...
...that it...
...does.
그래
- 진짜야?
- 그럼, 물론이지!
-Are you sure?
-Sure, I'm sure!
만약 핵전쟁이 일어나서
살아남은 남자가 나뿐이라면
There's a nuclear holocaust.
I'm the last man on earth.
Would you go out with me?
나랑 데이트할래?
그래
I've got canned goods.
통조림도 많아
Take a look at this!
얘들아, 이걸 봐
Check this baby out!
Dug me a hole.
근사하지?
내 구덩이야
Excellent hole, Joe.
절묘한 구덩이로다
Oh, no! My hole!
안돼! 내 구덩이!
My foot!
왜 그래?
What is it?
Jellyfish sting!
It hurts!
해파리한테 쏘였어
엄마야! 나 죽어!
Can we help you to the house?
- 집에 데려다줄까?
- 3킬로나 되잖아
It's two miles.
구덩이 파다
힘 다 빠졌어
And I'm tired from digging.
망할 해파리...
못된 해파리들!
Damn the jellyfish!
Damn all the jellyfish!
Do something.
- 방법이 없을까?
- 한 가지가 있긴 한데
There's only one thing.
그게 뭐야!
What is it?
Pee on it.
쏘인 데다
오줌 누면 돼
뭐? 끔찍해!
Gross!
디스커버리 채널에서 본 거야
I saw it on Discovery Channel.
맞아, 암모니아 성분이
진통제 역할을 할 거야
He's right.
There's ammonia in that...
...that kills the pain.
Forget it.
It doesn't hurt that bad!
됐어, 참을 만해!
You can use my hole for privacy.
남들 눈이 무서우면
내 구덩이를 쓰도록
I'm ready to get
the hell out of here.
난 이 집을 당장 뜨련다
오, 너희들...
Are you?
너희들?
That's so great!
정말 잘됐다
Not for Bonnie.
보니만 불쌍하지
니들은 좋겠다
But for you, yea!
-How was the beach?
-Nothing. I don't know.
- 재미있었어?
- 아냐, 몰라
-What happened?
-Nothing.
- 왜 그래?
- 아냐, 샤워할래
-I'm going to shower.
-Me too.
나도
Me too.
I'll put this in the car.
이거 차에 둬야겠다
I have to go pack!
짐 싸야지
-And it really does?
-lt does.
- 진짜 그래?
- 그럼, 정말로 진실로 그래
It really and truly does.
It so does not!
전혀 그렇지 않아!
우리 관계가 잘못된 게
모두 나 때문이래
She wants me to take responsibility
for everything that went wrong.
다섯 장에 걸쳐
내 부정을 탓하고 있어
She goes on for five pages
about how I was unfaithful to her.
We were on a break!
우린 그때 깨진 상태였어!
맙소사, 또 그 소리 했다간
나랑 깨질 줄 알아
If you say that one more time,
I'll break up with you.
This breakup was not all my fault.
She says here...
하지만 다 내 잘못은 아냐
이걸 한번 들어봐
..."lf you accept full responsibility...
'모든 책임을 진다면
다시 널 믿어볼게'
...I can begin to trust you again.
Does that seem like
something you can do? Does it?"
'그 정도는 해줄 수 있지?
안 그래?'
아니
You have what you want.
You're back with her.
네가 원하던 대로 됐잖아
이걸 문제 삼으면
몽땅 공중분해라고
If you bring this up now,
you'll wreck it.
Yeah, I know.
You're right.
알아, 맞는 말이야
I'll let it go.
내가 져야지, 하지만
덮어두긴 힘든 문제야
But you know how hard it is
to forget this?
Sure, it's hard...
덮어두긴 힘들겠지만
꼭 얘기할 필요가 있나?
...but you don't have to talk about it.
A lot happened on that trip...
우리도 발설하기 곤란한
해변의 사연들이 많거든
...that we should
never, ever talk about.
대체 무슨 일이 있었는데
What happened on that beach?
바다와 우리만의 비밀이야
It's between us and the sea, Ross.
나야
Hi, Ursula.
그래
지금 와서 이런 얘긴
뭐하지만
I know that we haven't talked
in a long time.
우리 엄마가 생모가 아니라
다른 여자가 우리 생모래
Our mom is not our birth mom.
This other lady is our birth mom.
Right, the one that lives in Montauk.
그래, 몬토크에 사는 여자
You know her?
- 아는 분이야?
- 아니, 엄마 유서에서 읽었어
No. I read about her
in Mom's suicide note.
유서도 있었어?
아직도 갖고 있어?
There was a suicide note?
Do you still have it?
Hang on.
기다려
유서 얘기는 한마디도
없었잖아
I can't believe you didn't tell me
there was a suicide note.
Yeah, so how have you been doing?
그래, 어떻게 지냈니?
그게... 시끄러워!
Shut up!
"Goodbye, Phoebe and Ursula.
I'll miss you.
'안녕, 피비와 우르술라
보고 싶을 거다'
P.S. Your mom lives in Montauk."
'추신, 너희 생모는
몬토크에 산단다'
You just wrote this!
언니가 방금 쓴 거잖아
It's pretty much the gist.
요점만 간추렸어
Except for the poem.
You read the poem, right?
시만 빼고,
그 시 읽었지?
아니
All right. Hang on.
알았어, 대기
Pass the cheese, please.
치즈 좀 줄래?
You can't even look at me, can you?
내 얼굴도 안 볼 거야?
그럼
It's Phoebe!
We can talk to Phoebe!
피비랑 얘기하면 되겠다!
지금 얘기할 기분 아냐
I'm too depressed to talk.
I'll give you $1000 to talk to us.
우리하고 얘기하면
천 달러 줄게
What about making that
beach trip an annual thing?
이봐, 매년 해변에
놀러가는 게 어때
싫어!
무슨 일이 있었는데?
What happened out there?
What? We took a walk.
Nothing happened.
뭐가? 그냥 산책했지
일은 무슨 일
I came back with nothing all over me.
멀쩡하게 돌아왔다고
What happened?
Joey?
답답해 죽겠다, 조이?
- 좋아...
- 안돼!
All right.
We swore we'd never tell.
입 다물기로 맹세했지?
They'll never understand.
쟤들은 이해 못해
We have to get it out.
It's eating me alive!
뭔가 얘기는 해야지
이러다 속 터져 죽겠다
- 모니카가 해파리한테 쏘였어
- 좋아!
-Monica got stung by a jellyfish.
-All right!
좋다고
I got stung.
해파리한테 쏘였어
Stung bad.
치명적이었지
I couldn't stand.
서있을 수도
걸을 수도 없었어
I couldn't walk.
We were two miles from the house.
집까지는 3킬로미터
We were scared and alone.
외롭고 두려웠어
가망이 없어 보였지
We didn't think we could make it.
I was in too much pain.
통증이 너무 심했어
난 구덩이 파다
파김치가 됐고
And I was tired from digging.
Then Joey remembered something.
근데 조이가 뭔가를 기억했어
디스커버리 채널에서 봤지
I'd seen it on Discovery Channel.
Wait, I saw that.
그래, 나도 봤어
디스커버리 채널
맞아, 해파리 독침은...
On the Discovery Channel.
About jellyfish and how if you
자기 발에 오줌을 눴어?
You peed on yourself?
You can't say that!
You don't know!
잘 알지도 못하면서
함부로 말하지 마
I thought I would pass out.
아파서 기절할 뻔했어
I tried, but I couldn't...
어쨌든 노력은 해봤지만
자세가 영 안 나오더라
...bend that way.
그래서...
That's right.
I stepped up.
그래, 내가 나섰다!
She's my friend and she needed help.
친구가 고통을 당하고 있잖아
If I had to,
I'd pee on any of you.
필요하다면 누구한테든
오줌 갈길 수 있어
Only...
근데... 못하겠더라
...I couldn't.
I got the stage fright.
무대공포증이 있어서
I wanted to help,
but there was too much pressure.
돕고 싶었지만
너무 부담이 커서...
챈들러한테 넘겼어
So I turned to Chandler.
Joey kept screaming at me,
"Do it now. Do it. Do it now!"
얘가 막 소리를 지르잖아
'뭐해! 빨랑 싸! 빨랑! '
Sometimes, late at night,
I can still hear the screaming.
아직도 밤이면 가끔
그 소리가 들려
Because I do it through my wall
to freak you out.
내가 벽에 대고
지르는 소리야
Maybe there's somebody
you guys could talk to.
어디서 상담을 받아봐
Oh, who?
누구랑, 이렇게
떼를 지어서?
It's not like they have a group
for people like us.
그래, 오웬이 최고야
Yeah, no, there's this
guy Owen, he's the best.
Might have his card.
명함이 있을 텐데
자홍색과 담자색
And fuchsia and mauve
내 침실의 66가지 색이라네
Those are the 66 colors of my bedroom
감사합니다
I invite all of you to count
the colors in your bedroom.
모두들 자기 침실의
색깔을 세어 보세요
Except for you.
You go away.
아줌마는 그냥 가보시죠
I'll go in a second.
이 말만 하고 금방 가마
I just want to tell you...
너희를 버리고 하루라도
후회 안 한 날이 없다
...there wasn't a day
I didn't regret giving you up.
Okay, bye.
네, 그랬군요
I'm not done.
내 얘기 끝까지 들어라
너희를 찾지 않은 건...
The reason I never
looked you up was because...
...I was afraid you'd react...
지금 같은 반응이
나올까 두려워서였어
...just like the way
you're reacting now.
Can't we just start from here?
Please?
지금부터 시작하면 안될까?
No.
싫어요
그래...
Sorry.
죄송해요
One last thing.
마지막으로 한 가지
넌 가족을 찾았잖아
You came looking for family.
I'm family.
엄마가 가족이야
I'm it.
맞아
그게 다야
Now I'm done.
It's not like we're losing anything.
둘 다 손해날 거 있나요?
I guess you're right.
네 말이 맞다
It's not like we know each other
or have anything in common.
서로 모르는 사람이고
닮은 데도 없어요
I don't know.
It's not like...
글쎄, 닮은 구석이
있는지도 모르지
...we don't have anything in common.
I mean, I like pizza.
난 피자를 좋아하는데
저도 좋아해요!
I like pizza!
Wait, I like the Beatles.
- 잠깐, 난 비틀즈가 좋아
- 엄마야, 저도 그래요!
Oh, my God!
So do l.
- 그리고 강아지는 어때요
- 너무 귀엽지
Puppies.
Cute or ugly?
So cute!
You see?
거 봐
But I'm still mad at you.
- 그래도 엄마가 미워요
- 안다
I know.
I'm mad at me too.
나도 내가 미워
Do you want to get something to eat?
I'm kind of hungry.
뭐 좀 드실래요?
전 배가 고픈데요
- 저런, 나도 그래!
- 그거 묘하네요
Hey! Me too!
Uncanny.
비가 오려나 본데
우산이 없어요
It looks like rain
and I don't have my umbrella.
나도 없어
비 맞는 거 싫은데
Me neither. I really hate that.
Stop it. Now you're just
doing it to freak me out.
그만, 자꾸 무서워져요
자기가 그리웠어
I missed you.
I missed you too.
나도
I was so nervous about that letter.
편지 때문에
얼마나 신경을 썼든지
But the way you
owned up to everything...
자기 행동을 보니까
철이 많이 든 것 같아
...it just showed me
how much you've grown.
I suppose.
그럴 거야
You have, Ross.
You should give yourself credit.
정말 대단한 일을 해냈어
My mom never thought
this would work out.
엄마는 절대
안 될 거라고 했지
She said, "Once a cheater,
always a cheater."
'한 번 바람둥이는
영원한 바람둥이야'
I just wish we hadn't
lost those four months.
넉 달을 허송세월했어
But if time was what you needed
to gain a little perspective....
그 동안 보는 눈이 좀
넓어졌다니 다행이지만
이건 깨지는 관계야!
We were on a break!
-Coffeehouse?
-You bet.
- 카페로 갈까?
- 좋지
우리 관계가 꼬인 건
둘 다한테 잘못이 있어
It took two people
to break up this relationship.
You and that girl, which yesterday
you took full responsibility for.
그래, 너하고 어제 네가
책임지겠다던 그 여자
무슨 책임인지 알 게 뭐야
편지도 다 못 읽었는데
I didn't know what
I took responsibility for.
I didn't finish the letter.
- 뭐?
- 잠들었다고
I fell asleep.
You fell asleep?
잠들었어?
It was 5:30 in the morning.
새벽 5시 30분이었어
편지는 무려 18장이었고
And you had rambled on for 18 pages.
Front and back!
앞뒤로 꽉꽉!
그리고 YOU'RE는
YOU ARE란 뜻이야
By the way, Y-O-U-apostrophe-R-E
means "you are."
Y-O-U-R means "your."
YOUR가 아니라고!
I can't believe I thought of getting
back with you! We are so over.
다시 합칠 생각을 하다니
내가 정신이 나갔지, 끝났어
Fine by me!
피차일반이외다!
Those spelling tips will be handy
Saturday nights at home...
철자교정은 주말에 모니카랑
낱말게임 할 때나 해주시지
...playing Scrabble with Monica.
- 야...
- 미안하다
Sorry!
All that sleep you'll miss
wishing you were with me!
날 그리워하며 잠을
못 이룰 텐데 어쩌니?
Don't worry about me falling asleep.
내 잠자리 걱정하지 마
아직 네 편지 갖고 있으니까!
I still have your letter!
Just so you know,
it's not that common.
잘 들어둬
그게 아무 남자한테나 생기는
복인 줄 아나 본데 정신 차려!
It doesn't happen to every guy.
And it is a big deal!
I knew it!
그렇다니까!
Gin.
'진'이야
We were playing gin?
이게 '진'이었어?
우리가 연인이라면
다 벗고 할 텐데
If we were a couple,
we could play naked.
-Would you stop?
-Okay. All right.
- 그만 좀 해
- 알았어
All right.
좋아, 넌 괜찮은 애야
I think you're great.
I think you're sweet and smart...
자상하고 똑똑하고
...and I love you.
널 사랑해
But you'll always be the guy
who peed on me.
평생 내게 오줌을 갈긴
남자로 남을 거야